hi everybody I'm Jimmy Rainsford i'm
here at Romeo and welcome to this
YouTube lesson where we're going to be
talking about how to learn drum fills by
ear and now everyone wants to learn drum
fills drum fills all the fun part of
playing drums and yeah they're great
and I want to just break down how you
would learn them by ear not writing them
down not using manuscript paper and just
listening to phil and really really
breaking it apart
so I'm just going to play at a simple
fill a little a little bit on the
complicated side but we can break down
talk about so here we go
ok cool Phil quite simplistic and sounds
great around the kid he can move around
all the toms and let's break it down
ok let me just play the Phil again same
speed
ok the first thing you want to be
listening for is how long of the space
damn well actually take up for this Phil
it's taking up one full bars or one full
bar soul
ok that's the full length of the fill
and identify that first second thing you
got to identify is not wise
what's going on the fill so if we count
a bar and we listened to the Phil it's
going to dinner
ok so let's just play that out so 123
for those notes one bar
let's move it to the snare ok so I'm
same again
if you're here to fill that I was doing
a few minutes ago it almost has that
kind of feel it has like a did it did it
did it did it today
ok and it's good to be able to sing the
phils that like it just even just sing
them to yourself and get used to fill in
your head and i'm now for that certain
Phil it's good to kind of pick apart
which drum is where ok at where does the
snare fall
where does each Tom get played you know
when exactly is the bass drum come in
you know you know the amount of notes in
the Phil now it's just about placing
which drums are playing what
so we're not certain fill it has this
kind of rhythm
ok the snare is still playing that back
beat on the fill
okay that's one thing you can identify
any any groove or in any fill as well as
the snare still playing the backbeat try
to fill and and as you heard i just
played with my hands I didn't use my
feet at all
so let's now move on to what the phil
actually is with my feet
listen out for weather scenarios like I
said that's enough for the Tom's for mr.
for room where the bass drum false
so for that certain Phil let's try it
again this time I'm using my based on
ok ok
straightaway we've identified the fill
of identified idea the lengths to fill
we've identified amount of notes to fill
now we've identified the orchestration
felt what drugs between and these little
tips can just make you break down a drum
fill a lot easier
don't don't listen to a drum fill and
think straight away oh it's this certain
way
really concentrate on it listen / -
again listen to where he's leading how
is leading back what symbol is going to
if you're watching the drummer player
look at what he's doing between his
hands and his feet you know some things
can get very very complicated but most
of the time it's going to be the
simplest answer you know if you can if
you can do the simplest way and it still
sounds great
go and do it if you like this you can go
subscribe to drop your engine
below and you gotta turn into a free
trial and you also get tons of content
there's a i did my i did my course on
refining your groove where we talked
about lots of things like this and so
please go and check it out it can be it
it's gonna be so helpful and I hope you
got something from it so thanks very
much
yeah