hello everybody my name is eric Moore
and I am very very pleased to be here
you all want to give you guys a great
exercise that's going to build your foot
speed like everybody always asks me Eric
how do you get your foot to move so fast
how do you get to play what you play
well a lot of things I used to do
especially now that I'm older playing
different styles of music and rock music
i like to use this certain exercise so
I'm gonna give you guys an example
I like to start out with the metronome
so if you have a metronome
you can send it out whatever temple that
works best for you
okay you've got to start at your own
speed whatever is best for you i'm going
to start out at 65 BPM
here's the exercise
what I really notice about this exercise
for one
you're really really keeping a strong
steady pace with your foot that that's
giving you a double in the beginning and
it's not a triple but it's three notes
so three consisting mostly with a nice
space
so even when you're playing other beasts
you can play the different rhythms
but this one foot exercise is going to
build that calf muscle that you need in
order to get your foot to do what you
have to do everything takes practice
so you have to start slow and you gotta
start from somewhere
also for those of you i'm just taking
this out for some of you that don't play
with your heel up how some people play
with their foot down
so let's try it with the hill down also
now i'm going to speed it up
let's take it up from 65 to 75 BPM take
it up even faster
all healed up
5b pm's i'm going to go up to 95 PPM's
pick it up even faster
I'm telling you the more you do this
exercise the more your foot will start
to burn baby
got to get that burn going
I'm so i'm pretty sure it's starting to
kick in now and having a little
difficulty hard to keep that temple
going
but hey this is how you get better man
you got to keep on pushing yourself
I'm gonna take it up to 115 k
yeah
so let me give you an example of how
playing this and using this at this
temple will definitely get your foot to
move faster
that'll get your doubles working your
trip was going and you could incorporate
this in all different styles of your
music just a great foot exercise k
that's how you build also remember
there's lots of drum your lessons on
drugs.com
you can check it down at the link below
be sure to check it out
also it's a free subscription for 30
days all those that try outs you know
gmail.com
man check it out so here we go I'm a
player than a couple of different groups
hope you enjoy
yeah